# Scott Shepherd

UX and Graphic Designer

scott@scotts.design 206-356-4695 www.linkedin.com/in/scott-shepherd/

# **Objective**

Full-time Designer position in a tech company.

#### Introduction

I have been an owner/ partner at a startup for the past 3 years, where my agency used an Agile philosophy to accomplish everything from small business needs to tier 1 company software solutions. I've performed various roles in a product lifecycle from Designer, Creative Director, Product Owner, Scrum Master, to Delivery Manager. Having skills in UX Design, Graphic Design, Marketing, Project Management, Communication, and Software Development.

There are 3 tactics that I have found to be most effective when it comes to project success and team collaboration:

- 1. The Amazon Backwards Press Release, which first defines the goal and vision of the product by going to the stakeholders and figuring exactly what it is that needs built before working backwards to define all the steps needed.
- 2. User Stories, which define the experience that the users will have when using the product. This is invaluable for exploring and explaining the growing needs and emotional attachment behind the experience and product.
- 3. Agile (Scrum) methodology, which pulls the team together and creates an efficient environment for iterative production and development.

Portfolio: www.scotts.design, created using Bootstrap, HTML5, and CSS3.

## Technologies I use

- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe InDesign
- Adobe Premiere
- Adobe After Effects

- Adobe Experience Design
- Invision
- Sketch
- Zeplin
- HTML5

- CSS3
- Bootstrap
- Github
- Microsoft Office
- JIRA
- Slack

## **Recent Experience**

Creative Director, UX Designer and Graphic Designer at Solid State Pros <a href="https://www.solidstatepros.com">www.solidstatepros.com</a>

2014 - 2017, As Creative Director and UX Designer I facilitated branding and UX projects with design teams.

#### Notable Projects:

**Stoel Rives LLP: Tombolo,** proprietary software for a tier 1 company used to ticket and escalate incidents in a privacy suite.

My roles: Designer, Associate Product Owner, and Client Manager

- Lead a design team towards a simple and clear user interface.
- Used **Adobe Illustrator** to create mockups for review and a pixel perfect design for developers.
- Worked directly with developers to guide implementation of features and requirements.
- Worked directly with the client to help define user stories and timelines.

**Hyle Mobile: TrueTap**, <u>www.truetap.mobi</u> mobile app designed to facilitate the assessment and value of a mobile device and direct them towards nearby resellers.

My roles: User Researcher, UX designer, Brand Team member, and QA tester.

- Used Adobe Illustrator to create concepts and mockups for branding and UX direction.
- Helped define research direction and findings presentation.
- **Face to face interviews** with potential customers to define personas.

**Skybridge LLC:** <u>www.skybridgesolution.com</u> Outsourcing manufacturing company rebranding to approach US tech market.

My roles: Brand Lead, UX Designer, Graphic Designer, Co-Developer and a Researcher.

- Lead a branding team to create concepts, moodboards, and mockups.
- Used Adobe Illustrator to create logos for reviews, iterations, illustrations, and a final logo.
- Performed research into user base, potential clients, and current competitors in order to create something original and impressionable.
- Using a **Bootstrap** template I used **HTML5** and **CSS3** to co-create the website.

**Merry Go Ride:** <a href="http://adobe.ly/1UECsd8">http://adobe.ly/1UECsd8</a> Create a style guide, UX design, developer schemata, and clickable prototype for a ride service app for children. My roles: Brand lead, UX Designer, and Graphic Designer

• Using **Adobe Experience Design** I create a clickable prototype, style guide, UX design, and developer schemata in one easy location.

**Lake City Hub**: <a href="https://xd.adobe.com/view/45c5bc76-0967-413e-aa42-52029463094e/">https://xd.adobe.com/view/45c5bc76-0967-413e-aa42-52029463094e/</a> Create a UX design and clickable prototype for the Lake City Hub application.

My roles: Project Manager, UX Designer, and Graphic Designer.

• Using **Adobe Experience Design** I created a clickable prototype

**Epicmeet**: <u>www.epicmeetapp.com</u> Produce a commercial for Epicmeet, an app designed to bring boardgamers together, that appeals to its key demographic using a limited budget for live action video.

My roles: Producer, Director, Editor, and Screenwriter.

- I planned the project with a limited budget using **MS Excel**.
- Hired a director of photography, actors, makeup artist, and crew.
- Facilitated the rental and logistics behind equipment.
- Scouted locations
- Co-wrote the screenplay in **MS Word**.
- Co-created our shot list
- Picked out music and sounds
- Co-edited the footage with **Adobe Premiere**
- Facilitated hosting and linking with marketing website.

**Vett.cloud**: www.vett.cloud Create a brand, logo, style guide, and 2 animated videos conveying value and explaining the product, which brings together stakeholders in a project and lets them analyze an opportunity anonymously.

- Using **Adobe Illustrator** to create mockups, and **MS Excel** to bring collaboration and decision making to the team.
- Using **Adobe After Effects** to create an animation highlighting the value proposition of the product: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=51Art4ZguLo">www.youtube.com/watch?v=51Art4ZguLo</a>
- Using **Adobe Audition**, **Adobe Illustrator**, and **Videoscribe** to create a white boarding animation that explains the product: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zNpHRFvx4a0">www.youtube.com/watch?v=zNpHRFvx4a0</a>

Project Manager at Motive LLC <u>www.createmotive.com</u>

2017, As Project Manager I facilitated design and development for various client websites.

**Gelotte Hommas Drivdahl Website**: Facilitate the development of designed comps.

My role: Project Manager

- Using **Adobe Illustrator** adjust and export various assets as needed for development.
- Using **JIRA** to track the production workflow.

Creative Director, UX Designer, and Brand Strategist for NED Learning <a href="https://www.nedlearning.com">www.nedlearning.com</a>

2016 - 2017, As Creative Director I facilitated branding, character, graphic, and UX design on various projects. I also run the social media accounts.

• Using **Adobe Illustrator** I created a logo, brand assets, a learning board game, and worksheets.

#### **Education**

## Bachelor of Science in Cognitive Psychology

Evergreen State College 2000-2003

This included computer science courses, logic, and discrete mathematics.

#### Bachelor of Arts in Media Production

Evergreen State College 2000-2003

This included communication, organizational, and marketing studies.

#### Continuing Education

I do daily studies on Lynda.com and other online learning platforms in order to continually improve myself. Recent certifications from these include:

- Sketch for UX Design
- UX Design Techniques: Analyzing User Data
- UX Design Techniques: Creating Personas
- UX Design Techniques: Creating Scenarios and Storyboards
- UX Design Techniques: Ideation
- UX Design Techniques: Paper Prototyping
- HTML5: Structure, Syntax, and Semantics

## References

Steve Haak: CEO and VP of Strategy at Solid State Pros LLC, 206-407-9689 Stephen Morrissey: Program Manager at Sinclair Digital, 206-475-1290 Daniel Carpenter: CEO and Senior Designer at Motive LLC, 206-795-0189 Kieran O'Mahony: Neuroscientist at UW and NED Learning, 206-499-0176 Paul Clifton: Associate System Administrator at Nintendo, 208-982-7115